🎄 **[Holiday hours](#holiday-hours)**

Now offering Therapy in over 40 states!  **[Find yours](http://adhdonline.com/teletherapy)**

Privacy policy
==============

**Mentavi, Inc. d/b/a ADHD Online**

**Privacy Policy**

Last updated November 7, 2023

Effective June 15, 2018

**Information Collected By Mentavi Health/ADHD Online (“ADO”)**

When you interact with ADO through its website(s) located at [www.adhdonline.com](http://www.adhdonline.com/) and www.mentavi.com, and any other U.S. website where we may post this Privacy Policy, we may collect information from you, as further described below. As part of the operation of the ADO main website, we gather certain types of information from users. Since your privacy is important to us, we would like to explain the types of information we gather, what we do with said information, and how to correct or change the information. This Privacy policy is incorporated into our Terms and Conditions. 

This Privacy Policy applies only to services provided by ADO and Mentavi, Inc. (“Services”) Except as provided herein, this Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by us outside of those Services, including on any other website operated by us or any third party, or data collected outside of the Services by ADO providers. It also does not apply to the information practices of any third party, including third parties you may communicate with off the Services, or third parties you connect with through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on our Services.

Mentavi, Inc. operates the websites and provides administrative services to ADO Medical, but does not provide medical services and is not a medical group. All medical services are provided by independent medical groups, including ADO Medical, P.C. (“Medical Groups”) which are not owned or operated by Mentavi, Inc. These medical groups and their employed or contracted providers (“Providers”) comply with all applicable state and federal laws regarding the privacy of your health information and in accordance with their own Notice of Privacy Practices.  If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy or the Notice of Privacy Practices, you may not use or access our Services. 

**Information You Provide**

We collect two main types of information from users:

First, your personal contact information is voluntarily provided when you register for our Services. This may include but is not limited to personal data such as name, zip code, email address, mailing address, and demographic information. Second, we collect your health information. This could include the information you complete via the online comprehensive mental health assessment, as well as a copy of any of your health records and/or other health information that ADO and/or the Medical Groups might request from you for use in an ADHD assessment and/or diagnosis and treatment. All such health information is handled according to all applicable ethical and legal requirements, including state and federal laws and regulations..

**Automatic collection** – When you interact with us through one of our websites, we receive and store certain information on usage patterns. We may store such information, or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by affiliates, agents, or service providers. ADO may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to our site. 

**Aggregated information** – Aggregated information, such as which pages users visit, is collected through various means. One of these ways is through an IP address, a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. Web servers, the computers that “serve up” Web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When you make a request from the ADO website, our servers log your IP address. ADO logs IP addresses for the purposes of system administration only. In an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of our websites, we may conduct research on our user demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information collected. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate, anonymized basis, and we may share this aggregate data with our affiliates, agents, and partners. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics to describe our mission, products, events, and services to current and prospective clients, and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.

**Use of Cookies** – ADO uses cookies to automate the process of logging on to the ADO website(s). A cookie is a small data file stored on your computer that contains a single, randomly assigned user ID number. Cookies can neither read any other files on your computer nor damage your computer. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. You can disable cookies by changing your browser settings. Further information about how to disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website. ADO may use third-party website analytic tools such as Google Analytics, among others, on our websites that employ cookies to collect certain information concerning your use of our websites. Additionally, some of the third-party analytics tools we use also use “tracking pixels” to record log data such as open rates for emails. We encourage you to research the aforementioned tools’ privacy policies if you are concerned about their handling of information.

**How we use your information.** We use the information you provide in a manner that is consistent with both HIPAA and this Privacy Policy. If you provide information for a certain reason, we may use the information in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you sign up for an email newsletter, we will use the information to send you said newsletter. If you contact us by email, we will use the information you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem. If you provide information in order to obtain access to ADO Services, we will use your information to provide you with access to such Services and to monitor your use of such Services. ADO and its affiliates may also use your information collected through our websites to help us improve the content and functionality of our sites, and to better understand our users. ADO may use this information to contact you in the future to tell you about any of our Services we believe might be of interest to you. If we do so, each marketing communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to “opt out” of receiving future marketing communications. In addition, if at any time you wish not to receive any future marketing communications or you wish to have your name deleted from our mailing lists, please contact us as indicated below. Lastly, Mentavi, Inc. provides the Medical Groups and Providers with certain administrative services such as website maintenance and providing administrative staff. Information provided to ADO may be used to provide the administrative services or to improve such administrative services. 

**Where information is processed. ADO** is based in the United States. No matter where you are located, you consent to the processing and transferring of your information in and to the U.S.

**Disclosure of your information.** ADO does not sell your information. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you.

There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your information with certain third parties, as set forth below:

**Consent:** We may transfer your information with your consent.

**Affiliates:** We may also share your information with our affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties:** Like many organizations, we sometimes hire other companies or individuals to perform certain mission-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases, and processing payments.

**Legal Requirements:** We may disclose your information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of ADO or its affiliates, (iii) protect the personal safety of users of our websites or the public, or (iv) protect against legal liability.

**Aggregated or Non-identifiable Data:** We may also share aggregated or non-personally identifiable information with our partners or other third parties for business purposes.

**Children.** ADO does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 and believe he or she has disclosed personal information to us please contact us via the contact form on our website. ADO will not knowingly engage in processing for users under the age of consent established by applicable data protection law. If we learn that we are engaged in that processing with such users, we will halt such processing and will take reasonable measures to promptly remove applicable information from our records.

**Links to other sites.** This Privacy Policy applies only to ADO website(s). ADO website(s) may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us. The policies and procedures described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to aforementioned sites. The links from ADO website(s) do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed the aforementioned sites.

**Data retention.** We generally retain personal data for so long as it may be relevant to the purposes identified herein. To dispose of personal data, we may anonymize it, delete it or take other appropriate steps. Data may persist in copies made for backup and mission continuity purposes for additional time.

**Security.** ADO understands the need for user privacy and access to user data is strictly limited and can only be accessed by specific individuals who have the necessary credentials and qualifications. We take reasonable steps to protect the information provided to us from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or email transmission is ever fully secure or error-free. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any information via the Internet.

**Your data rights.** You can unsubscribe from certain emails by clicking the “unsubscribe” link they contain. You can opt out from certain cookie-related processing by changing the proper settings in your browser.

**How can I access the personal data you have about me?** If you would like to submit a data access request, you can do so by submitting an email to [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We will then start the process by confirming your identity and then provide you with an email containing the personal data that ADO has on you within 30 days. Your continued use of ADO website(s) after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with the terms of said revised Privacy Policy.

**How do I correct, update, amend, or delete the personal data you have about me?** You may request other modifications from by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

 **Protected Health Information**

When you set up a User Account with us, you are creating a direct customer relationship that enables you to access and/or utilize our services. As part of that relationship, you provide information to us, including but not limited to, your name, email address, shipping address, phone number and certain transactional information that are not “protected health information” or “medical information.”

However, in using certain components of the services, some of the information we collect may constitute “protected health information” (“PHI”) under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”). While we are not a “covered entity” as defined in HIPAA, one or more of the Medical Groups and its Providers, and/or other health care providers engaging with you through our Services may be a “covered entity” or “business associate” under HIPAA and therefore subject to HIPAA, and we may in some cases be a “business associate” of a Medical Group or Providers. Please note that HIPAA does not necessarily apply to an entity or person simply because there is health information involved, and HIPAA may not apply to your transactions or communications with us, the Medical Groups, and/or the Providers. To the extent we are deemed a “business associate” however, and solely in its role as a business associate, ADO may be subject to certain provisions of HIPAA with respect to PHI. In addition, any medical or health information that you provide that is subject to specific protections under applicable state laws (collectively, with PHI, “Protected Information”), will be used and disclosed in accordance with such applicable laws. However, any information that does not constitute Protected Information under applicable laws may be used or disclosed in any manner permitted under this Privacy Policy. Protected Information does not include information that has been de-identified in accordance with applicable laws.

The Medical Groups and its affiliated Providers have adopted a Notice of Privacy that describes how they use and disclose PHI. By accessing or using our services to interact with a Medical Group and/or Provider, you acknowledge that you have received and agreed to the Notice of Privacy Practices from your Medical Group and/or Provider(s). 

If we collect, use, and discloses Protected Information on behalf of your Medical Group or Provider, such processing on behalf of your Medical Group or Provider shall be consistent with the Notice of Privacy Practices and as permitted in our agreements with the Medical Groups or Provider, except to the extent you have expressly authorized additional uses and disclosures. We may, on behalf of the Medical Groups or Providers use PHI for purposes of treatment, payment, and health care operations, including to communicate with you, to provide requested services, to provide information to your Medical Groups or Providers, pharmacies, and insurers, to obtain payments for our services, and to communicate with your Medical Groups or Providers, pharmacies, and benefits program. We may combine your PHI with other information about you, including information from other sources, such as from your Medical Groups or Providers, pharmacies, insurers or benefits program, in order to maintain an accurate record of our users. We may use your PHI to contact you for any services or products offered by ADO or the Medical Groups. 

**Additional Information for California Residents**

This Section 11 supplements the other information contained in our Privacy Policy and applies solely to California residents (“consumers” or “you”). This Section provides additional information on how we collect, use, and share your “personal information” (as defined in the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”)). This Section applies only to the extent required by the CCPA, so some personal information about Californians is not covered by this Section. For example, this Section does not apply to PHI and “medical information” as defined in California’s Confidentiality of Medical Information Act. It does not apply to personal information we collect from our employees and job applicants in their capacity as employees and job applicants. It also does not apply to personal information we collect from employees, owners, directors, officers, or contractors of businesses in the course of our provision or receipt of business-related services. Any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this Section. 

Categories of Personal Information ADO Collects 

During the 12 months leading up to the date of this Privacy Policy, we may have collected all of the information described in Section 2 of our Privacy Policy from and about California residents. We collect this information in the ways and from the sources described in Section 2 above, and we may use this information in the ways described in Section 3 above. The information we collect generally falls into the following categories, to the extent that it is personally identifiable:

* Identifiers such as name, phone number, mailing address, email address, and User Account information (such as username and password), IP address, online identifiers, and device identifiers;
* Financial information such as payment card number, and insurance information such as insurance policy number, if you use insurance to purchase a Service or product;
* Health and medical information, such as your medical history and information we derive from health symptoms and health information;
* Protected characteristics such as your age, gender, religion, race and ethnicity;
* Commercial information such as purchase history;
* Internet or other electronic network activity information such as information about domain names, landing pages, browsing activity, content or ads viewed and clicked, dates and times of access, pages viewed, forms you complete, search terms, and uploads or downloads;
* Professional or employment-related information such as the name and address of the company you work for, in connection with insurance requests;
* Audio and visual information, such as audio, video, and images of you;
* Geolocation information such as your precise or approximate location; and
* Other personal information, such as date of birth and any other personal information you share with us.

Using and Sharing Personal Information 

We may use any of the categories of personal information for the purposes stated above with the third parties listed below, to provide you with the Services, and to other parties with your consent. We share your personal information with the following affiliated and non-affiliated parties, for any of the purposes above:

* Our affiliates.
* Service Providers (as defined above and in the CCPA) that provide us with services to support our operations, such as customer service, email management, analytics, and IT providers.
* A third party, including another company, during the negotiations for and if we undergo a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other transaction in which that third party assumes control of our business (in whole or in part). 
* Government authorities and law enforcement, if we are required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
* Other third parties, for purposes of fulfilling our legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order, or other legal process, such as preventing, detecting, and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities; protecting the rights, property, or safety of you, us, or another party; enforcing any agreements with you; responding to claims; and resolving disputes.
* With your consent, or as otherwise directed by you.

The CCPA sets forth certain obligations for businesses that “sell” (as defined in the CCPA) personal information to third parties. Based on our understanding of the definition of “sell,” we do not “sell” your personal information and have not done so in the prior 12 months from the effective date of this Policy. 

Your CCPA Rights

If you are a California resident, the CCPA allows you to make certain requests about your personal information. Specifically, the CCPA allows you to request us to:

* Inform you about the categories of personal information we collect or disclose about you; the categories of sources of such information; the business or commercial purpose for collecting your personal information; and the categories of third parties with whom we share/disclose personal information;
* Provide access to and/or a copy of certain personal information we hold about you;
* Delete certain personal information we hold about you; and
* Provide you with information about the financial incentives that we offer to you, if any.

The CCPA further provides you with the right not to be discriminated against (as provided for in applicable law) for exercising your rights. Please note that certain information may be exempt from such requests under California law. For example, we need certain information in order to provide the Services to you. 

For security and legal reasons, we reserve the right to refuse requests that require us to access third-party websites or services. We also reserve the right to verify your identity to our satisfaction before responding to your request. When verifying requests, our verification standards vary depending on the sensitivity of the request. If we cannot verify your identity, we may deny your request. In some cases, we may require additional information, in which case we will contact you.

For more information regarding your legal rights under California law or if you want to exercise any of them, or if you are an authorized agent making a request on a California consumer’s behalf, please call us at 888-493-2343 or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Please include a detailed description of the right you want to exercise and whether you want to exercise this right with regard to some or all of your personal information.

“Shine the Light” Disclosure

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (California’s “Shine the Light” law) gives California residents the right under certain circumstances to request information regarding our disclosure of certain categories of personal information (as defined in the Shine the Light law) to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. We do not share your personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy.** ADO reserves the right to change the policy on use of information collected. Any changes in policy will be noted through a change in the “last updated” date in Privacy Policy statement. You may direct any Privacy Policy questions to our website. Your continued use of ADO website(s) after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with the terms of said revised Privacy Policy.

**Contact us.** If you have questions or inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy or ADO’s handling of user information, feel free to contact us through our website.

### Contact us

### Company

### More info

### Get our newsletter

Phone: [888-493-ADHD (2343)](tel:888-493-2343)  
Monday – Friday  
9:00 AM – 5:00 PM EST

Name 

Email 

Subscribe

### Contact us

Phone: [888-493-ADHD (2343)](tel:888-493-2343)  
Monday – Friday  
9:00 AM – 5:00 PM EST

### Company

### More info

### Join our email list

Name 

Email 

Subscribe

If you have a concern about the safety and quality of care, please contact ADHD Online’s Chief Compliance Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

© 2024 Mentavi Health, Inc. All Rights Reserved. | [Privacy policy](https://adosandboxsite.wpenginepowered.com/privacy-policy/) | [Notice of privacy practices](https://adosandboxsite.wpenginepowered.com/notice-of-privacy-practices/) | [Terms & conditions](https://adosandboxsite.wpenginepowered.com/terms-conditions/) | [No Show & Refund policy](https://adosandboxsite.wpenginepowered.com/refund-policy/)

If you have a concern about the safety and quality of care, please contact ADHD Online’s Chief Compliance Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

© 2024 Mentavi Health, Inc. All Rights Reserved. | [Privacy policy](https://adhdonline.com/privacy-policy/) | [Notice of privacy practices](https://adhdonline.com/notice-of-privacy-practices/) | [Terms & conditions](https://adhdonline.com/terms-conditions/) | [No Show & Refund policy](https://adhdonline.com/refund-policy/)

**If you are having suicidal thoughts, please immediately call or text the Suicide & Crisis Lifeline at 988**  

On Friday, October 25th, our phone and chat services will be unavailable from 1-5 PM ET, but we’re still here for you! Please [submit a request ticket](https://adhddiagnosis.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) or leave us a voicemail at 888-493-2343, as our team will continue processing these requests. We appreciate your understanding.

**The ADHD Online Team**

We know Hurricane Milton is impacting many in Florida. Clinicians and patients may face challenges attending scheduled appointments without prior notice. Additionally, filling prescriptions may be difficult due to store closures. We’ll work with you to reschedule your appointment once conditions improve. Your safety and well-being are our top priorities. Stay safe!

**The ADHD Online Team**

### Join Our ADHD Research Study

Mentavi Health is conducting ADHD research and is accepting a limited number of participants. Participants in our clinical study will get an ADHD Assessment at no cost. 

**Who can join?**

* Age 19+
* Primary language is English
* Not previously diagnosed with ADHD
* Not a current patient of ADHD Online or Mentavi Health
* A resident of any of the 50 US states or DC (not including Puerto Rico or other territories)

**Why participate?**

Your involvement will help improve mental health care for everyone.

Live support will be unavailable during regular business hours on Wednesday, December 25, and Wednesday, January 1. You can always [submit a request](https://adhddiagnosis.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) or leave a voice message. We’ll get back to you when we return.

Please note: Each of our clinicians sets their own holiday hours, check with them for their schedule.

**Looking to take our Mentavi Smart Assessment? That’s available all day, every day, whenever and wherever is best for you!**

Our site is open 24/7! You can always [schedule an appointment](https://patients.adhdonline.com/dashboard/appointments?_gl=1*1yqkghk*_gcl_au*NTI3Nzk4MzQ1LjE2OTkyODMxNTc.), [check out](https://adhdonline.com/get-answers/resources/) our podcasts, or read up on the latest ADHD information.

#### **Provide [this form](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1W63Lv39xTnDufGJFXq4LLdJ6sEdV3Djd) to your local practitioner. You could:**

* Send this link
* Email the pdf
* Print it out and bring it to your appointment

#### **Ask your practitioner**  
**to complete [the form](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1W63Lv39xTnDufGJFXq4LLdJ6sEdV3Djd)**

In this form, your practitioner will request that ADHD Online continue to provide uninterrupted care

#### **Return** **the form to us**

You or your practitioner can return this form to us [\[email protected\]](https://adhdonline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)or fax it to 616-210-3118
